<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Getting Started on Velociraptor - Digging Deeper!</title>
    <link>/categories/getting-started/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Getting Started on Velociraptor - Digging Deeper!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>/docs/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Velociraptor can be used in a number of contexts and deployed in a number of different way. The following pages will help you get started quickly.
Most people want to start a single server and client and check out the GUI. This way you can see how Velociraptor can be useful to you immediately. You can read about this installation method in the &amp;ldquo;Standalone Deployment&amp;rdquo; page.
If you deploy the server in the cloud it is possible to use automatically minted SSL certificates and Single Sign On for authentication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations and Workshops</title>
      <link>/docs/presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/presentations/</guid>
      <description>We present about Velociraptor frequently in conferences and workshops.
This page highlights some of the more interesting presentations we gave. It can be used as reference material. Note the dates of presentation as some material may be outdated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Triaging</title>
      <link>/docs/getting-started/triaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/getting-started/triaging/</guid>
      <description>We can use Velociraptor to hunt for many artifacts across the network. However ultimately, the Velociraptor agent simply runs VQL to collect its artifacts. What if we can just collect the artifacts interactive?
We certainly can do this!
Triaging a system. When triaging a system our goal is to collect and preserve as much data from the system as possible, as quickly as possible.
First lets see what artifacts come built in with Velociraptor:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial</title>
      <link>/docs/tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/tutorial/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial we will deploy Velociraptor locally to our machine, and connect a client to it. This is the bare minimum required to demonstrate Velociraptor&amp;rsquo;s capabilities and walk through the GUI.
Velociraptor can be used in a number of different ways, but in this tutorial we will use it as an end point visibility tool, collect some artifacts and set up endpoint monitoring.
Overview Before we start it is useful to see how a Velociraptor deployment looks at a high level:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>