<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gui on Velociraptor - Hunt Evil!</title>
    <link>/categories/gui/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gui on Velociraptor - Hunt Evil!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/gui/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Artifact Types</title>
      <link>/docs/user-interface/artifact_types/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/user-interface/artifact_types/</guid>
      <description>Velociraptor uses VQL for many different purposes. Since Artifacts are a nice way to package VQL queries, there are a number of different types of artifacts. This page documents some of the more common artifact types and where they are used.
Client Artifacts Client artifacts encapsulate VQL queries that run on the client. The artifact contains a number of Sources - each extracting a single table of data.
Client artifacts are collected from the each client at a time, or using a hunt, collected from a number of clients at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Velociraptor Artifacts</title>
      <link>/docs/user-interface/flows/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/user-interface/flows/</guid>
      <description>Velociraptor&amp;rsquo;s main job is to collect Forensic Artifacts. An artifact is simply a yaml file which tells Velociraptor how to collect a set of files or information in order to answer a specific question.
Artifact definitions Artifacts are supposed to be defined and tweaked by the user. Therefore they are defined using YAML in a simple file format.
Below is an example of a typical artifact definition.
name: Windows.Sys.Users description: | List User accounts that were logged into the machine in the past by searching for registry artifacts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>